<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blogposts on Rust in Blockchain</title>
    <link>https://rustinblockchain.org/categories/blogposts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blogposts on Rust in Blockchain</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rustinblockchain.org/categories/blogposts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RiB is One Year Old!</title>
      <link>https://rustinblockchain.org/blogposts/2020-07-30-rib-is-one-year-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rustinblockchain.org/blogposts/2020-07-30-rib-is-one-year-old/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey, RiB community!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce that RiB is one year old &amp;ndash;
happy birthday to RiB!
This is a late celebration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we released &lt;a href=&#34;https://rustinblockchain.org/newsletters/2019-06-06/&#34;&gt;Rust in Blockchain #0&lt;/a&gt; on June 6th, 2019,
we have published 14 issues, along with 2 additional blog posts.
With more than 20 contributors participating!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next issue is on the way, and we will publish it on next Wednesday.
Contributions to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rust-in-blockchain/rust-in-blockchain/tree/master/draft&#34;&gt;next draft&lt;/a&gt; are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime,
let&amp;rsquo;s take this opportunity to look back at what we accomplished,
and recognize those who helped along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-we-started-rib&#34;&gt;Why we started RiB&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We thought that,
although the Rust community is vibrant,
and although there were many Rust blockchain projects,
those Rust blockchain projects didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have a strong voice in the Rust community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While talking to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Argorak&#34;&gt;Florian&lt;/a&gt; about how to create
spaces within the official Rust infrastructure for people to discuss
blockchain subjects,
he suggested that we first create a newsletter,
like &lt;a href=&#34;https://this-week-in-rust.org/&#34;&gt;This Week in Rust&lt;/a&gt;,
specifically for Rust blockchain subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we did that,
and we created a Telegram group,
and a Twitter handle,
and invited other people to participate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several people helped create RiB:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The newsletter idea for RiB came from &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Argorak&#34;&gt;Florian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first issue was made with help from &lt;a href=&#34;https://alexandraheller.com/about/&#34;&gt;Alexandra&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/gnunicornBen&#34;&gt;Benjamin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ashchan&#34;&gt;James Chen&lt;/a&gt;, and Mike, who also manages the RiB Telegram group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sunhuachuang&#34;&gt;Sun&lt;/a&gt; created and maintains &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rust-in-blockchain/awesome-blockchain-rust&#34;&gt;Awesome Blockchain Rust&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://echoqi.net/&#34;&gt;Echo&lt;/a&gt; designed the RiB logo and other related graphics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contributors-to-rib-community&#34;&gt;Contributors to RiB Community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, many people have contributed to the newsletter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adria0&#34;&gt;Adria Massanet&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gluk64&#34;&gt;Alex Gluchowski&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/oxarbitrage&#34;&gt;Alfredo Garcia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AnaisUrlichs&#34;&gt;Anais Urlichs&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/calvinlauco&#34;&gt;Calvin Lau&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/da-kami&#34;&gt;Daniel Karzel&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/darosior&#34;&gt;Darosior&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jlwaugh&#34;&gt;James Waugh&lt;/a&gt;,
Ken Shamir,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lrettig&#34;&gt;Lane Rettig&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MPtherealMVP&#34;&gt;María Paula&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mat7ias&#34;&gt;Mattias Nystrom&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nearmax&#34;&gt;Maksym Zavershynskyi&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mfaulk&#34;&gt;mfaulk&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/michaelsproul&#34;&gt;Michael Sproul&lt;/a&gt;,
Mike,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/majecty&#34;&gt;Park Juhyung&lt;/a&gt;,
Paulii Good,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/somniumism&#34;&gt;SeungMin Lee&lt;/a&gt;,
Taylor Lee,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tarcieri&#34;&gt;Tony Arcieri&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://brson.github.io/&#34;&gt;Brian Anderson&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://impl.dev/about/&#34;&gt;Aimee Zhu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your contributions.
You made the RiB community great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sponsors-and-supporters&#34;&gt;Sponsors and Supporters&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last year, RiB got two cups-of-coffee donations in ETH! Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nervos.org/&#34;&gt;Nervos Network&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lsquo;s sponsoring, we organized RiB meetups, In Rust We Trust,
in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/Rust-in-Blockchain-San-Francisco/events/262773260/&#34;&gt;SF&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/Rust-in-Blockchain-Berlin/events/263526816/&#34;&gt;Berlin&lt;/a&gt;, and in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/Rust-in-Blockchain-Hangzhou/events/264778357/&#34;&gt;Hangzhou, China&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to SF Blockchain community,
and sponsors Nervos, Polkadot, Oasis, NEAR, Xpring, Insight,
we made full-day workshops &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/rust-in-blockchain-workshop-day-sfbw19-tickets-75088875849&#34;&gt;Rust in Blockchain Workshop Day&lt;/a&gt;
during &lt;a href=&#34;https://sfblockchainweek.io/&#34;&gt;SF Blockchain Week&lt;/a&gt; 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for all your support!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers&#34;&gt;Numbers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ours is a relatively small community,
perhaps reflecting the niche interests we serve,
or perhaps that we haven&amp;rsquo;t put in enough effort to find our audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until now, RiB has 200+ unique visitors on average per day &amp;ndash; unfortunately, we lost the early data while moving the hosting from WordPress
to GitHub + Cloudflare. The screenshot shows the data from Cloudflare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/numbers-cloudflare-2020-07-30.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;227 Telegram members,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;485 Twitter followers,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;592 email subscriptions,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No data for RSS subscriptions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RiB GitHub repos &lt;a href=&#34;https://rustinblockchain.org/&#34;&gt;RiB Newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rust-in-blockchain/awesome-blockchain-rust&#34;&gt;Awesome Blockchain Rust&lt;/a&gt; got 166 stars in total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;changes-in-rib&#34;&gt;Changes in RiB&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The newsletter changes as we gain experience,
and is getting longer, with more project coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The regular project coverage has grown from 5 projects in the first issue to
14 projects in the latest issue: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rustinblockchain.org/newsletters/2020-07-01-stuck-inside-hacking-away/&#34;&gt;RiB Newsletter #13 – Stuck inside, hacking away&lt;/a&gt;.
For more and new Rust blockchain projects,
we add them to the &amp;ldquo;Interesting Things&amp;rdquo; section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rustinblockchain.org/awesome-blockchain-rust/&#34;&gt;Awesome RiB&lt;/a&gt; page shows almost all the projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RiB is intended not to be just a newsletter,
but a community where people interested in Rust blockchain subjects,
across projects,
can come together to discuss technical subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has not turned out exactly as anticipated:
our Telegram group is relatively small and inactive,
though the population and volume of discussion do seem
to trend slowly higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group has not been a great driver of technical discussion &amp;ndash;
those discussions seem to happen in project-specific venues.
Most of the discussion in-group stems from project representatives
posting project news.
This is good for the newsletter,
but we&amp;rsquo;re not sure what to make of RiB as a community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, communities have a life of their own,
and ours does seem to be serving a purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One notable trend that we didn&amp;rsquo;t anticipate,
though we probably should have,
is that recruiters sometimes use our Telegram group
as a way to get access to candidates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our attitude toward posting recruiting messages in the group
has been inconsistent &amp;ndash;
we do have a policy of keeping discussion to technical topics,
and sometimes shut down recruiting and marketing talk,
but sometimes go with it,
perhaps steering the discussion toward project-specifics,
for the sake of encouraging discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re not sure what to think about this.
In any case, job listings are always welcome in the newsletter. We&amp;rsquo;ll help retweet as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-to-expect-in-the-future&#34;&gt;What to Expect in the Future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the second year of RiB, we hope to add more original technical content,
as well as expand to cover topics on cryptography, security, consensus, VMs, and crypto-economics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for now.
Thanks for your time.
Keep hacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow us on Twitter &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rust_blockchain&#34;&gt;@rust_blockchain&lt;/a&gt;, or join in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/rustinblockchain&#34;&gt;RiB Telegram discussion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How RiB Newsletter is Generated</title>
      <link>https://rustinblockchain.org/blogposts/how-rib-newsletter-is-generated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rustinblockchain.org/blogposts/how-rib-newsletter-is-generated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rust in Blockchain publishes a monthly newsletter that shares relevant technical content to the Rust blockchain development community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, we will introduce how our monthly newsletter is generated, the content structure and the workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope it will be easier for you to contribute to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rust-in-blockchain/rust-in-blockchain/tree/master/draft&#34;&gt;next issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rib-newsletter-structure&#34;&gt;RiB Newsletter Structure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each month introduction: summary of the month&amp;rsquo;s events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thanks:
a list of all the contributors to this issue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project Spotlight: one cool project each month, per our preference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interesting Things:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interesting Rust &amp;amp; blockchain projects, GitHub repos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Articles, particularly on cross-cutting technical topics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter threads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anything that you think is interesting to the community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most Active in each month: a list of projects with the most GitHub activities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project Updates:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub activity numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;News&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blog posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Videos and podcasts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Important or interesting GitHub PRs and issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Events: developer related blockchain events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Careers: a list of developer jobs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;content-generation&#34;&gt;Content Generation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every month we&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Call for contribution one week ahead of the publish date (will introduce publish date in the next section)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accept contribution from GitHub, deal with PRs and issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accept contribution from other channels. e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rust_blockchain&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;hi@rib.rs&#34;&gt;Email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/rustinblockchain&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate newsfeed from projects&amp;rsquo; RSS subscription&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run Ribbot one day ahead to calculate GitHub data from projects in rib-bible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss on Introduction, Spotlight, Interesting Things sections (we gather some of the content from reading news randomly)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review the final draft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create the next draft file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publishing&#34;&gt;Publishing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RiB Newsletter publishes on the first Wednesday of each month (Pacific time), towards the end of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publish the newsletter. Technically, we move the current issue from draft folder to content folder, build and deploy it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy the published page to Mailchimp and send newsletter to email subscriptions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share the published page to Twitter, Reddit, Hacker News, and some related groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future, we will optimize our workflow to make it more efficient and easier to contribute to. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rust-in-blockchain/rust-in-blockchain/tree/master/draft&#34;&gt;next draft&lt;/a&gt; is ready to accept contributions ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please let us know your thoughts and suggestions anytime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join RiB &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/rustinblockchain&#34;&gt;Telegram group&lt;/a&gt; for community discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Contributors</title>
      <link>https://rustinblockchain.org/blogposts/call-for-contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rustinblockchain.org/blogposts/call-for-contributors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s build the Rust Blockchain community together!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the first publication of the Rust in Blockchain newsletter, I have been receiving great feedback — people are excited about the potential of Rust blockchain projects uniting together to create a greater community. When I started this newsletter just a few months ago, I didn&amp;rsquo;t imagine I would so quickly get so much encouraging
support from people all over the world, including Germany, Italy, England, the US, and China. I am so grateful. There is something special and brilliant in this intersection of technologies and communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this newsletter is to collect and disseminate useful news and information about the many Rust blockchain projects, in the hopes it will spur collaboration and connections between Rust blockchain engineers. I believe great minds are alike, and that the combined talents of the Rust blockchain community can do incredible things for the entire blockchain industry. We are still at the very early stage in blockchain engineering, and we are the ones who build the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the more I talk to developers, the more I understand that bringing together the many individual Rust blockchain communities, elevating Rust blockchain technology to the become something truly exceptional, is something I can&amp;rsquo;t do on my own. Not only are there simply too many Rust blockchain projects for me to follow and coordinate with, but I myself am not an engineer (yet &amp;hellip;) — my passion is bringing engineers together to create great things, but I still need help understanding the technical developments and their significance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is a call to those Rust and blockchain developers who believe in the power of community, and who want Rust to be the language of choice for blockchain projects. Blockchain is a huge domain for Rust, and Rust is a huge advantage to blockchain developers. Together we can do great things, and speak with a powerful voice, both to the world of Rust, and to the world of blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever your skillset — developer, writer, editor, designer — Rust blockchain projects need people interested in building community, ecosystems, applications, tools, documentation, tutorials, and more. There&amp;rsquo;s no end of interesting work ahead. Some of the roles the community is in most need of include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;developers who want to blog about technical subjects related to Rust blockchain technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;developers to build on Rust blockchain platforms (and maybe blog about what they are doing :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;developers familiar with individual Rust blockchain projects who can identify the monthly news most important to their project, for inclusion in this newsletter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;community organizers who want to organize local Rust in blockchain meetups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rust blockchain organizations who will donate space and resources for meetups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;web developers to help with the maintenance of this newsletter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly where we are going yet, but I have ideas, and I bet you have ideas too. If you want to work together on making Rust and blockchain the best they can be, a good place to start is by joining the Rust in Blockchain &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/rustinblockchain&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;. And you can always email me, Aimee, at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:aimeez@pm.me&#34;&gt;aimeez@pm.me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to hearing from you. Let&amp;rsquo;s build the future together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
