<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blogposts on Rust in Blockchain</title>
    <link>https://rustinblockchain.org/categories/blogposts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blogposts on Rust in Blockchain</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rustinblockchain.org/categories/blogposts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How RiB Newsletter is Generated</title>
      <link>https://rustinblockchain.org/blogposts/how-rib-newsletter-is-generated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rustinblockchain.org/blogposts/how-rib-newsletter-is-generated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rust in Blockchain publishes a monthly newsletter that shares relevant technical content to the Rust blockchain development community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, we will introduce how our monthly newsletter is generated, the content structure and the workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope it will be easier for you to contribute to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rust-in-blockchain/rust-in-blockchain/tree/master/draft&#34;&gt;next issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rib-newsletter-structure&#34;&gt;RiB Newsletter Structure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each month introduction: summary of the month&amp;rsquo;s events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thanks:
a list of all the contributors to this issue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project Spotlight: one cool project each month, per our preference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interesting Things:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interesting Rust &amp;amp; blockchain projects, GitHub repos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Articles, particularly on cross-cutting technical topics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter threads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anything that you think is interesting to the community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most Active in each month: a list of projects with the most GitHub activities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project Updates:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub activity numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;News&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blog posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Videos and podcasts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Important or interesting GitHub PRs and issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Events: developer related blockchain events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Careers: a list of developer jobs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;content-generation&#34;&gt;Content Generation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every month we&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Call for contribution one week ahead of the publish date (will introduce publish date in the next section)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accept contribution from GitHub, deal with PRs and issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accept contribution from other channels. e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rust_blockchain&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;n3wh4x0rs@gmail.com&#34;&gt;Email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/rustinblockchain&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate newsfeed from projects&amp;rsquo; RSS subscription&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run Ribbot one day ahead to calculate GitHub data from projects in rib-bible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss on Introduction, Spotlight, Interesting Things sections (we gather some of the content from reading news randomly)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review the final draft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create the next draft file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publishing&#34;&gt;Publishing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RiB Newsletter publishes on the first Wednesday of each month (Pacific time), towards the end of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publish the newsletter. Technically, we move the current issue from draft folder to content folder, build and deploy it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy the published page to Mailchimp and send newsletter to email subscriptions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share the published page to Twitter, Reddit, Hacker News, and some related groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future, we will optimize our workflow to make it more efficient and easier to contribute to. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rust-in-blockchain/rust-in-blockchain/tree/master/draft&#34;&gt;next draft&lt;/a&gt; is ready to accept contributions ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please let us know your thoughts and suggestions anytime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join RiB &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/rustinblockchain&#34;&gt;Telegram group&lt;/a&gt; for community discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Contributors</title>
      <link>https://rustinblockchain.org/blogposts/call-for-contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rustinblockchain.org/blogposts/call-for-contributors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s build the Rust Blockchain community together!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the first publication of the Rust in Blockchain newsletter, I have been receiving great feedback — people are excited about the potential of Rust blockchain projects uniting together to create a greater community. When I started this newsletter just a few months ago, I didn&amp;rsquo;t imagine I would so quickly get so much encouraging
support from people all over the world, including Germany, Italy, England, the US, and China. I am so grateful. There is something special and brilliant in this intersection of technologies and communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this newsletter is to collect and disseminate useful news and information about the many Rust blockchain projects, in the hopes it will spur collaboration and connections between Rust blockchain engineers. I believe great minds are alike, and that the combined talents of the Rust blockchain community can do incredible things for the entire blockchain industry. We are still at the very early stage in blockchain engineering, and we are the ones who build the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the more I talk to developers, the more I understand that bringing together the many individual Rust blockchain communities, elevating Rust blockchain technology to the become something truly exceptional, is something I can&amp;rsquo;t do on my own. Not only are there simply too many Rust blockchain projects for me to follow and coordinate with, but I myself am not an engineer (yet &amp;hellip;) — my passion is bringing engineers together to create great things, but I still need help understanding the technical developments and their significance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is a call to those Rust and blockchain developers who believe in the power of community, and who want Rust to be the language of choice for blockchain projects. Blockchain is a huge domain for Rust, and Rust is a huge advantage to blockchain developers. Together we can do great things, and speak with a powerful voice, both to the world of Rust, and to the world of blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever your skillset — developer, writer, editor, designer — Rust blockchain projects need people interested in building community, ecosystems, applications, tools, documentation, tutorials, and more. There&amp;rsquo;s no end of interesting work ahead. Some of the roles the community is in most need of include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;developers who want to blog about technical subjects related to Rust blockchain technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;developers to build on Rust blockchain platforms (and maybe blog about what they are doing :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;developers familiar with individual Rust blockchain projects who can identify the monthly news most important to their project, for inclusion in this newsletter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;community organizers who want to organize local Rust in blockchain meetups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rust blockchain organizations who will donate space and resources for meetups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;web developers to help with the maintenance of this newsletter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly where we are going yet, but I have ideas, and I bet you have ideas too. If you want to work together on making Rust and blockchain the best they can be, a good place to start is by joining the Rust in Blockchain &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/rustinblockchain&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;. And you can always email me, Aimee, at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:aimeedeer@gmail.com&#34;&gt;aimeedeer@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to hearing from you. Let&amp;rsquo;s build the future together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
